Ryan Rich Director of Design

rrich.io rrichrs@gmail.com Portland, OR 503-334-9134

Highly skilled product designer and developer with a penchant for creating quality software. Possesses a strong ability to lead technical and creative teams. Proven skills in user experience, front-end development, art direction and user interface design.

Experience

Director of Design — Catalyze, Inc.

<u> 2015 - Present</u>

Lead the end-to-end design of the entire suite of product offerings. Hired and managed a team of designers and front-end developers. Lead a large scale company-wide rebrand. Lead all user interface development. Created and delivered on KPIs and OKRs.

Lead Product Designer — Catalyze, Inc.

2014 - 2015

Lead digital product design. Integrated with the engineering team utilizing an agile development process. Designed, prototyped, and developed features using Angular JS, HTML/CSS, and Sketch. Reported directly to the CPO and CTO. Worked directly with stakeholders and lead design sprint sessions.

Front-end Web Developer — Global Thinking

2013 - 2014

Worked directly with leading brands such as Audi, Volkswagen and Ducati. Built Ruby on Rails applications. Worked with JavaScript MVC frameworks. Presented solutions to clients. Was directly responsible for building a custom search integration for a large fortune 500 company.

Co-founder & Designer — Gradesnap

2011 - 2013

Owned the entirety of product design and product marketing. Raised seed capital and graduated from two business accelerators. Built a software application that allowed teachers to grade tests with the cameras on their phone.

Education

R.I.T — B.S Applied Arts & Sciences
2013 Summa Cum Laude Graduate — 3.9 GPA

Skills & Knowledge

UI/UX Design HTML/CSS JavaScript Product Design & Development Director level management Team Building

Adobe CS Sketch JIRA, Trello, Asana, etc.